<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on</title><link>https://nickmcgrath.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nickmcgrath.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>K8s Installing Grafana Prometheus and Loki</title><link>https://nickmcgrath.github.io/blog/k8s-installing-grafana-prometheus-and-loki/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 19:25:45 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nickmcgrath.github.io/blog/k8s-installing-grafana-prometheus-and-loki/</guid><description>Logging and Monitoring in k8s #
Logging and monitoring in Kubernetes are important for understanding the behavior and performance of a cluster. Logging allows tracking events and activities, while monitoring provides real-time visibility into the resource usage, performance, and availability of the cluster and its components. Together, they help detect and diagnose issues, troubleshoot problems and ensure the cluster is running smoothly.
Prometheus is an open-source monitoring and alerting system. It collects metrics from monitored targets by scraping metrics HTTP endpoints on these targets.</description></item><item><title>K8s Nginx Ingress Mod Security WAF</title><link>https://nickmcgrath.github.io/blog/k8s-nginx-ingress-mod-security-waf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 22:03:50 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nickmcgrath.github.io/blog/k8s-nginx-ingress-mod-security-waf/</guid><description>What the WAF? #
A web application firewall (WAF) is a security tool that monitors and controls incoming traffic to a web application. It is used to protect web applications from various types of attacks, such as SQL injection, cross-site scripting (XSS), and file inclusion vulnerabilities. WAFs also help to prevent unauthorized access to sensitive data and can be used to comply with security regulations. Overall, a WAF is an important tool to help keep web applications and the data they handle secure.</description></item><item><title>K8s Creating Multi Cloud Clusters</title><link>https://nickmcgrath.github.io/blog/k8s-creating-multi-cloud-clusters/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 16:20:51 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nickmcgrath.github.io/blog/k8s-creating-multi-cloud-clusters/</guid><description>Considerations for creating a multi cloud k8s cluster #
This is not a recommended way of setting up clusters, likely will not continue on this topic.</description></item></channel></rss>