<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on</title><link>https://nickmcgrath.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nickmcgrath.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installing Grafana Prometheus and Loki in k8s</title><link>https://nickmcgrath.github.io/blog/installing-grafana-prometheus-and-loki-in-k8s/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 19:25:45 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nickmcgrath.github.io/blog/installing-grafana-prometheus-and-loki-in-k8s/</guid><description>Logging and Monitoring in k8s #
Logging and monitoring in Kubernetes are important for understanding the behavior and performance of a cluster. Logging allows tracking events and activities, while monitoring provides real-time visibility into the resource usage, performance, and availability of the cluster and its components. Together, they help detect and diagnose issues, troubleshoot problems and ensure the cluster is running smoothly.
Prometheus is an open-source monitoring and alerting system. It collects metrics from monitored targets by scraping metrics HTTP endpoints on these targets.</description></item><item><title>K8s Nginx Ingress WAF</title><link>https://nickmcgrath.github.io/blog/k8s-nginx-ingress-waf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 22:03:50 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nickmcgrath.github.io/blog/k8s-nginx-ingress-waf/</guid><description>Introduction to Technologies #
NGINX is Kubernetes most popular ingress controller with powerful open source add-ons. We will be exploring using ModSecurity engine to secure our publicly exposed services.
NGINX by Kubernetes community is used to control external access to services by routing incoming traffic.
Minikube is a tool for running a single-node Kubernetes cluster locally on your computer, it allows developers to test and develop applications that run on Kubernetes.</description></item><item><title>Creating Multi Cloud K8s Clusters</title><link>https://nickmcgrath.github.io/blog/creating-multi-cloud-k8s-clusters/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 16:20:51 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nickmcgrath.github.io/blog/creating-multi-cloud-k8s-clusters/</guid><description>Considerations for creating a multi cloud k8s cluster #</description></item></channel></rss>